

ROHIT RANJAN

• DETAILS •

New Delhi India +91-8861898799 rohitranjan2705@gmail.com

LINKS •Linkedin

• SKILLS •

SLA Management
Stakeholder Communication
Training and Development
Team Management
Quality Analysis
Escalation Management
Root Cause Analysis
Task Delegation
Conflict management

Google Adwords & Hotel Ads

Specialist

PROFILE

With an overall experience of ~8 years, I am an energetic and motivating leader with a proven ability to effectively manage both staff and long and short-term projects. I am also a self-starter and strong independent worker who excels at analyzing products and procedures in order to generate new ideas that improve efficiency and quality.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Operations Team Lead at Vaco Binary Semantics LLP (onsite Google India), Gurgaon April 2018 — Present

- End to end support operation management across Tier 1 workflows. Stakeholder engagement, reporting, KRA adherence.
- Key Performance Indicators (KPI) trend report development and governance through WBRs, MBRs and QBRs.
- Employing innovative (lean/Six Sigma) strategies for metric target achievement, sustenance and improvement.
- Supervision and direction of 30+ team members to deliver exceptional performance timely to meet client Service Level Agreements (SLAs).
- Talent identification and retention, Bottom Quartile (BQ) management plan implementation using Performance Level Approach & Early Warning Systems.
- Leading Quality Excellence with Quality Assurance & effective Training and Development drives. Quality Goals > 95% consistently throughout successive quarters.
- Daily operational/administrative task management and delivery using Google based tools and dashboards. Designed and prepared technical reports, studies and related documentation.
- Developed and presented business cases, presentations and reports to senior management.

Production & Quality Engineer at Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited-services provided by Bholasingh Jaiprakash Construction Limited, Bengaluru

August 2016 — December 2017

- Execution of Fabrication & Erection works of Structural Steel at Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited's (BHEL) 1x370MW Combined Cycle Gas Based Power Plant in Yelahanka, Bengaluru.
- Monitoring & ensuring quality of fabricated steel structures as per BHEL's Field Quality Plan.
- Coordinated the efforts of 400 workers for timely completion of fabrication & erection of 10000MT Steel Structure as per Quality Standards set by BHEL.

Design Engineer at i3 Technologies Private Limited, New Delhi

July 2015 — August 2016

- Worked on Design & Development of a new electric vehicle being developed by the company. Designed all components & parts of the vehicle using SolidWorks as per Automotive Industry Standards. Monitored manufacturing of the designed products as per specification.
- Evaluating Techno-Commercial risk in manufacturing the designed parts.

EDUCATION

Masters of Business Administration (Finance & Supply Chain Management), Delhi Technological University, New Delhi

2020 - 2022

Bachelor of Engineering-Mechanical Engineering, Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum

2011 - 2015